Hayden Dansbury

♥ Nashville, TN ☑ hgdansbury@gmail.com • hdansbury.com in hdansbury • hdansbury

Summary

Data Scientist with 3 years of experience in data analytics and statistical modeling, specializing in advanced predictive models, and journal-publishable statistical analysis. Contributed to research downloaded over 500 times, supporting government, commercial, and educational applications.

Experience

Research Data Scientist

 $Brentwood,\ TN$

HCA Healthcare, GME

May 2022 - Present

- Utilized SAS and Python to perform advanced statistical analyses on complex healthcare datasets, uncovering actionable insights that led to measurable improvements in healthcare outcomes.
- \circ Applied SQL to extract and transform large-scale electronic health record data from Teradata and $Google\ BigQuery$, enabling efficient data processing and analysis.
- Designed and implemented robust research methodologies, enhancing data-driven decision-making and fostering innovation within the healthcare industry.

Data Analytics Intern

Brentwood, TN May 2020 - Aug 2020

LBMC, PC

- \circ Designed and developed custom, enterprise-level *Power BI* data visualizations, providing executive leadership with actionable business insights and enabling strategic decision-making.
- Developed a seasonally adjusted ARIMA model in *Python* to forecast revenue trends for upcoming financial quarters.
- \circ Extracted and transformed large datasets from the data warehouse using SQL, supplying data for key analytics projects.

Education

Lipscomb University

Aug 2018 - May 2022

Bachelor's of Science: Double Major in (Data Science ∠) and (Psychology ∠)

o GPA: 3.75/4.0

Projects

Seasonally Adjusted ARIMA Model for Revenue Forecasting

LBMC, PC

- Developed a seasonally adjusted ARIMA model to predict the next years revenue for an accounting firm. Visualized predicted revenue that partners used to plan for the next tax season.
- o Tools Used: Python, SQL, Jupyter. Libraries: Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Statsmodels

Artificial Intelligence for Tic-Tac-Toe

Github 🗹

• Developed and implemented AI models for Tic-Tac-Toe using Minimax algorithm, Q-Learning, and Deep Q-Networks to create an intelligent decision-making system, using Python and TensorFlow.

Skills

Languages: Python, SAS, SQL, R, HTML & CSS - Prior Experience: C++, Java, JavaScript

Technologies: Jupyter Notebook, Google GCP & BigQuery, Teradata SQL, MySQL, Power BI, Tableau, Git, Linux Skills: Machine Learning, Statistical Testing, Data Analysis & Visualization, Database Management, Research Methods

Selected Publications

○ Comparing the Re-Hospitalization Rates and Cardiac Mortality in CHF Patients
 Taking Torsemide Versus Furosemide

 ○ How Does ECT Treatment Affect the Changes of Future Psychiactric Hospitalizations?

A Retrospective Study

◦ Evaluating the Effect of Vitamin D Supplementation on Long Term Prednisone Dosage in Link

Link

Link

✓

Evaluating the Effect of Vitamin D Supplementation on Long Term Prednisone Dosage in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus